<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='http://alicebutts.github.io/' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
Alice Butts
</title>
<link>
http://alicebutts.github.io/
</link>
<description>
Stories, etc.
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Thu, 12 Jan 2017 22:51:03 -0500
</lastBuildDate>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<guid>
http://alicebutts.github.io/posts-output/2017-01-07-ask-not-for-whom-the-megabus-tolls/
</guid>
<link>
http://alicebutts.github.io/posts-output/2017-01-07-ask-not-for-whom-the-megabus-tolls/
</link>
<title>
Ask Not For Whom The Megabus Tolls, It Tolls For Thee
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/megabus.png&quot; alt=&quot;megabus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One megabus trip is every megabus trip in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;the&amp;#95;line&amp;#95;up&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Line Up&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I approach the megabus boarding area I must subordinate myself to the last person in the line by the chainlink fence. I ask if they are going to New York. They say, &quot;Yes, 5:45.&quot; I am the 6:15, and when they board I am first in line. Now people ask me if I am New York. The line grows long and people still go to the trouble of coming to the front to ask. When I say, &quot;Yes,&quot; I give an unwelcoming look in the hope that they will not stand at the front of the line. Sometimes they still do. When they do I look at the ground and take it, but if Mercury is in line with Venus I say, &quot;Actually, this is the front of the line.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;seat&amp;#95;selection&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Seat Selection&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every three weeks I choose a new seat. Some day I will find the seat that I won't feel carsick in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;the&amp;#95;only&amp;#95;constant&amp;#95;is&amp;#95;change:&amp;#95;all&amp;#95;good&amp;#95;things&amp;#95;must&amp;#95;end&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Only Constant Is Change: All Good Things Must End&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I struggle to fit my backpack at my feet, I close my eyes and picture the month when I was allowed to rest the backpack on the lower-level's empty space behind the front door. Then I would sit with room at the four seats around the table.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The month ended when a megabus woman snapped her fingers at me, and yelled until I was smushed with my bag and everyone else's at the table. It was Halloween and necessary for two teenagers to braid hair. One rested her face on the table in front of me. The other braided, dropping any loose strands at my feet on my bag. I saw the expression I wanted to make on the man in the patagonia sweater sitting across the table.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;algorithms&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Algorithms&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I choose my seat, I use machine learning to assess where people will not sit next to me. Once a season the bus will not be full and if my algorithms succeed I will have the seat to myself. Until then, I make sure to make eye-contact with every prospective seat partner. You can always tell a talker by their eyes. What you cannot identify:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;People who will speak on the phone. If Bosch was alive today he would re-paint his portrait of hell as sitting on a megabus next to a person having the same conversation about how Jonathan hurt his leg (&quot;very terrible, very terrible&quot;) to three different people back-to-back-to-back. Dante would rewrite the Inferno to include the circle of hell where your megabus seat partner calls her best friend to explain why she asked her fiancee for a prenup.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;People who will cough. I, too, cough.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;People who will text with the clicking sound turned on on their phone's keyboard&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;the&amp;#95;ride&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Ride&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The megabus is a place to hone compassion. When I get to a point where I am ready to throw somebody's grandma's phone down the bus's stairs and scream, &quot;No more Jonathan!&quot; I remember there is only one law of the bus: you only control the seat you bought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ride begins with The Announcement. Terse drivers on their night shift say, &quot;Philadelphia. Philadelphia bus.&quot; Average drivers say &quot;Don't use the front stair case.&quot; Drivers who wish they had pursued stand-up turn the front stair case spiel into a fifteen minute routine. It is funny the first time and sad the second. The third time I hear it, I turn to my seat partner and complain it is the same every ride.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We clatter through the strip malls, and the driver makes a new, special annoucement: we will be picking up passengers from a megabus that broke down. We all turn around in our seat to see everyone else's face. The bus is full.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then the strip malls are farther and farther apart and we are in the darkness of the Jersey expanse. Everyone has their phone chargers plugged in above them. They sway like umbilical cords. After the darkness come the false cities. Towers of red and yellow lights trick me into believing I am seeing a skyline. Then the smell of sulfur leaking into the bus trains me to see the smoke. It billows up and wraps mysterious gray cylinders and domes; we are thirty minutes away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just beyond the towers and smoke the bus slows and stops. Our fallen sister megabus sits on the side of the road. All her passengers are lined up against the highway's railing. Their sillouhettes are dark and for a moment the headlights of the bus illuminate their hopeless faces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our driver searches our bus and finds a single seat. I do not know how they picked the woman who took it. The other fifty or so passengers are still against the railing as our driver turns the key in our bus's ignition. I see the passengers' faces once more as we pull away. They are mine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I text my boyfriend, &quot;Ask not for whom the megabus tolls,&quot; and laugh at myself and feel carsick.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are at the tunnel soon. Rattling in the artificial light until we pop up in the true city. The boys behind me say things about the city I didn't know because they are not true: Central Park is 20 miles long, there are the twin towers, it's only a 20 minute ride underground. I push my way off the bus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500
</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
